<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><MD_Metadata xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:srv="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/srv" xmlns:gts="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gts" xmlns:xalan="http://xml.apache.org/xalan" xmlns:gco="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gco" xmlns:gml="http://www.opengis.net/gml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/gmd">
    <characterSet>
        <MD_CharacterSetCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_CharacterSetCode" codeListValue="utf8" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">utf8</MD_CharacterSetCode>
    </characterSet>
    <hierarchyLevel>
        <MD_ScopeCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_ScopeCode" codeListValue="dataset" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">dataset</MD_ScopeCode>
    </hierarchyLevel>
    <hierarchyLevelName>
        <gco:CharacterString>dataset</gco:CharacterString>
    </hierarchyLevelName>
    <contact gco:nilReason="missing"/>
    <dateStamp gco:nilReason="missing"/>
    <metadataStandardName>
        <gco:CharacterString>ISO 19139 Geographic Information - Metadata - Implementation Specification</gco:CharacterString>
    </metadataStandardName>
    <metadataStandardVersion>
        <gco:CharacterString>2007</gco:CharacterString>
    </metadataStandardVersion>
    <identificationInfo>
        <MD_DataIdentification>
            <citation gco:nilReason="missing"/>
            <abstract>
                <gco:CharacterString>The FAA, pursuant to Title 14 of the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) § 99.7, Special security instructions (SSI), has prohibited all UAS flight operations within the airspace defined under NOTAM FDC 7/7282 . Specific locations are described in the table and on the interactive map provided on this website. The TFRs extend from the surface up to 400 feet Above Ground Level (AGL), apply to all types and purposes of UAS flight operations, and remain in effect 24 hours a day, 7 days a week. WHAT UAS FLIGHT RESTRICTIONS HAVE BEEN PUT INTO PLACE?At the request of and pursuant to agreements with the Department of Defense and U.S. Federal security and intelligence agencies (“sponsoring Federal agencies”), the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) has implemented Special Security Instructions for Unmanned Aircraft System (UAS), issued as temporary flight restrictions (TFR) over select national security sensitive facilities located throughout the U.S.  These TFRs are established within the lateral boundaries of these facilities and extend from surface to 400 feet Above Ground Level (AGL). These TFRs apply to all UAS operations specifically including:·       Public aircraft operations conducted in accordance with a Certificate of Authorization or Waiver (COA).·       Civil aircraft operations (other than model aircraft), including those conducted in accordance with a COA and those conducted in accordance with the FAA’s small UAS Rule, 14 CFR Part 107.·       Model Aircraft operations conducted in accordance with 14 CFR Part 101, Subpart E.UAS operators must comply with these flight restrictions in addition to all other applicable Federal Aviation Regulations, including but not limited to, requirements to secure an FAA airspace authorization and/or waiver prior to flying in the airspace where a TFR is in effect.The information on this website complements Notice to Airmen (NOTAM) NOTAM FDC 7/7282, which generally notifies the public about these temporary flight restrictions (TFR).  This website provides UAS operators with more detailed information about these TFRs, including:·       An explanation of what is restricted·       A table listing the selected facilities over which a TFR has been established·       An interactive map providing visual depictions and information about specific TFRs and geospatial (GIS) data that can be downloaded·       An explanation of which UAS operations may be able to access the airspace within a TFR, including instructions for submitting a request·       Reminders on other requirements for UAS operationsWHAT HAPPENS IF I VIOLATE A TEMPORARY FLIGHT RESTRICTION (TFR)?The FAA classifies the airspace encompassed by these temporary flight restrictions (TFRs) as “national defense airspace” in accordance with Title 49 of the United States Code (USC) § 40103(b)(3).  Violations of these TFRs may prompt the following enforcement actions:A.   The U.S. Government may pursue criminal charges, including charges under Title 49 U.S.C § 46307.B.   The FAA may take administrative action, including imposing civil penalties and the revoking FAA certificates and authorizations to operate UAS under Title 49 U.S.C. §§ 44709 and 46301.WHAT ARE THE BASIC FLIGHT RESTRICTIONS?The FAA, pursuant to Title 14 of the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) § 99.7, Special security instructions (SSI), has prohibited all UAS flight operations within the airspace defined under NOTAM FDC 7/7282. Specific locations are described in the table and on the interactive map provided on this website. The TFRs extend from the surface up to 400 feet Above Ground Level (AGL), apply to all types and purposes of UAS flight operations, and remain in effect 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.See the full text of NOTAM FDC 7/7282 here.ARE THERE EXCEPTIONS FOR UAS OPERATIONS TO ACCESS A TFR?The FAA has authorized UAS operations within the TFRs if those flights are in compliance with the applicable requirements listed below:1) The UAS flight operation has been pre-approved by the designated facility contact based on criteria established by the sponsoring federal agency in coordination with the FAA. Note: UAS operators seeking approval to operate in one of the TFRs defined in this website under this provision must contact the facility’s designated point of contact identified in the table or interactive map, and secure permission to operate within the airspace prior to entry.  Pre-approval from the facility or sponsoring agency does not substitute for compliance with FAA requirements. Depending on the nature of the proposed operation and Class of airspace, waiver or authorization may be needed from the FAA before flight. For more information visit our website at www.faa.gov/uas2). The UAS flight operation is conducted in direct support of an active national defense, homeland security, law enforcement, firefighting, search and rescue, or disaster response mission, and prior notification has been provided to the designated facility contact. Note: UAS operators seeking approval to operate in one of the TFRs defined in this website under this provision must contact the facility’s designated point of contact identified in the table or interactive map, and provide notification prior to entering the airspace. These operators must make every effort to coordinate with the designated facility to deconflict the UAS flight operation with any safety or security concerns stated by the facility and/or sponsoring Federal agency.3). The UAS flight operation is conducted in direct support of a significant and urgent governmental interest and is approved by the FAA’s System Operations Support Center (SOSC) in advance of entering the TFR. Note: UAS operators, that meet the criteria for thisprovision , may also qualify for access under provision 2 outlined above and are encouraged to coordinate directly with the facility’s designated point of contact identified in the table or interactive map, by providing notification prior to entering the airspace and taking into consideration any safety or security concerns stated by the facility and/or sponsoring Federal agency. For urgent and time sensitive requests, contact the FAA’s SOSC at (202) 267-8276 for expedited assistance.  The FAA’s SOSC will coordinate with the facility and/or sponsoring Federal agency as appropriate.ARE THERE OTHER REQUIREMENTS TO OPERATE IN A TFR IN ADDITION TO THE EXCEPTIONS?Separate and distinct from any of the conditions cited above used to gain access to a TFR defined by NOTAM FDC 7/7282 and described in this website, UAS operators must comply with all applicable Federal Aviation Regulations.  For example:For Model Aircraft:·       Comply with 14 CFR Part 101, Subpart E NOTE: These provisions require model aircraft operators to notify any airport operator and air traffic control tower within 5 miles of the intended area of flight.For All Other UAS Operators:·       Comply with a Public Aircraft Certificate of Authorization or Waiver (COA), or·       Comply with 14 CFR Part107, Small Unmanned Aircraft Systems, or·       Comply with Section 333 Exemption and a Certificate of Authorization or Waiver (COA) NOTE: Public and civil UAS operators flying under the provisions of a COA or 14 CFR Part 107 may need to secure further airspace authorizations or waivers in order to conduct the proposed flight operation in controlled airspace, which may overlap with one of the TFRs defined by NOTAM FDC 7/7282 and this website.  In those cases, these operators should follow the pre-existing procedures outlined below. A.     Non-emergency requests for UAS airspace authorizations and waivers must be submitted using the regular process as follows:·       14 CFR Part 107 requests for airspace authorizations and waivers must be submitted to the FAA athttps://www.faa.gov/uas/request_waiver/·        Section 333 Exemption holders may request a site specific COA at https://oeaaa.faa.gov/oeaaa/external/uas/portal.jsp·       Public aircraft operators without an existing authorization to operate must secure a public COA athttps://ioeaaa.faa.gov/oeaaa/Welcome.jsp B.     Emergency requests for UAS authorizations/waivers for missions that directly support significant and urgent governmental interests (e.g., active national defense, homeland security, law enforcement, and emergency operations missions), which cannot be supported by the FAA’s routine authorization/waiver processes should be referred to the SOSC at (202) 267-8276ADDITIONAL QUESTIONS?If you have any general questions regarding UAS operations, please refer to the following FAA webpage: https://www.faa.gov/uas/ , or contact the FAA by email at uashelp@faa.gov or by phone at (844) FLY-MY-UA.If you have any additional questions regarding the TFRs defined by NOTAM FDC 7/7282 and this website, please contact the FAA SOSC at (202) 267-8276.DisclaimersThe restrictions depicted on this site reflect temporary flight restrictions issued for national security reasons at select U.S. Federal facilities. There may be additional temporary flight restrictions that prohibit UAS and manned flight in effect in your area. Seehttp://tfr.faa.gov/tfr2/list.html for additional information on flight restrictions that may be in effect in your area before operating your UAS.</gco:CharacterString>
            </abstract>
            <purpose>
                <gco:CharacterString>National Security UAS Flight Restrictions</gco:CharacterString>
            </purpose>
            <credit>
                <gco:CharacterString>Federal Aviation Administartion / ATO / System Operation Security, AJR-2</gco:CharacterString>
            </credit>
            <descriptiveKeywords>
                <MD_Keywords>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>UAS</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>                       Drone Restriction</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>                       National Security UAS Flight Restriction</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                </MD_Keywords>
            </descriptiveKeywords>
            <descriptiveKeywords>
                <MD_Keywords>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>UAS</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>                       Drone Restriction</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>                       National Security UAS Flight Restriction</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                </MD_Keywords>
            </descriptiveKeywords>
            <descriptiveKeywords>
                <MD_Keywords>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>UAS</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>                       Drone Restriction</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                    <keyword>
                        <gco:CharacterString>                       National Security UAS Flight Restriction</gco:CharacterString>
                    </keyword>
                </MD_Keywords>
            </descriptiveKeywords>
            <resourceConstraints>
                <MD_Constraints>
                    <useLimitation>
                        <gco:CharacterString>National Security UAS Flight Restrictions Over Select FacilitiesWHAT UAS FLIGHT RESTRICTIONS HAVE BEEN PUT INTO PLACE?At the request of and pursuant to agreements with the Department of Defense and U.S. Federal security and intelligence agencies (“sponsoring Federal agencies”), the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) has implemented Special Security Instructions for Unmanned Aircraft System (UAS), issued as temporary flight restrictions (TFR) over select national security sensitive facilities located throughout the U.S.  These TFRs are established within the lateral boundaries of these facilities and extend from surface to 400 feet Above Ground Level (AGL). These TFRs apply to all UAS operations specifically including:·       Public aircraft operations conducted in accordance with a Certificate of Authorization or Waiver (COA).·       Civil aircraft operations (other than model aircraft), including those conducted in accordance with a COA and those conducted in accordance with the FAA’s small UAS Rule, 14 CFR Part 107.·       Model Aircraft operations conducted in accordance with 14 CFR Part 101, Subpart E.UAS operators must comply with these flight restrictions in addition to all other applicable Federal Aviation Regulations, including but not limited to, requirements to secure an FAA airspace authorization and/or waiver prior to flying in the airspace where a TFR is in effect.The information on this website complements Notice to Airmen (NOTAM) NOTAM FDC 7/7282, which generally notifies the public about these temporary flight restrictions (TFR).  This website provides UAS operators with more detailed information about these TFRs, including:·       An explanation of what is restricted·       A table listing the selected facilities over which a TFR has been established·       An interactive map providing visual depictions and information about specific TFRs and geospatial (GIS) data that can be downloaded·       An explanation of which UAS operations may be able to access the airspace within a TFR, including instructions for submitting a request·       Reminders on other requirements for UAS operationsWHAT HAPPENS IF I VIOLATE A TEMPORARY FLIGHT RESTRICTION (TFR)?The FAA classifies the airspace encompassed by these temporary flight restrictions (TFRs) as “national defense airspace” in accordance with Title 49 of the United States Code (USC) § 40103(b)(3).  Violations of these TFRs may prompt the following enforcement actions:A.   The U.S. Government may pursue criminal charges, including charges under Title 49 U.S.C § 46307.B.   The FAA may take administrative action, including imposing civil penalties and the revoking FAA certificates and authorizations to operate UAS under Title 49 U.S.C. §§ 44709 and 46301.WHAT ARE THE BASIC FLIGHT RESTRICTIONS?The FAA, pursuant to Title 14 of the Code of Federal Regulations (CFR) § 99.7, Special security instructions (SSI), has prohibited all UAS flight operations within the airspace defined under NOTAM FDC 7/7282. Specific locations are described in the table and on the interactive map provided on this website. The TFRs extend from the surface up to 400 feet Above Ground Level (AGL), apply to all types and purposes of UAS flight operations, and remain in effect 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.See the full text of NOTAM FDC 7/7282 here.ARE THERE EXCEPTIONS FOR UAS OPERATIONS TO ACCESS A TFR?The FAA has authorized UAS operations within the TFRs if those flights are in compliance with the applicable requirements listed below:1) The UAS flight operation has been pre-approved by the designated facility contact based on criteria established by the sponsoring federal agency in coordination with the FAA. Note: UAS operators seeking approval to operate in one of the TFRs defined in this website under this provision must contact the facility’s designated point of contact identified in the table or interactive map, and secure permission to operate within the airspace prior to entry.  Pre-approval from the facility or sponsoring agency does not substitute for compliance with FAA requirements. Depending on the nature of the proposed operation and Class of airspace, waiver or authorization may be needed from the FAA before flight. For more information visit our website at www.faa.gov/uas2). The UAS flight operation is conducted in direct support of an active national defense, homeland security, law enforcement, firefighting, search and rescue, or disaster response mission, and prior notification has been provided to the designated facility contact. Note: UAS operators seeking approval to operate in one of the TFRs defined in this website under this provision must contact the facility’s designated point of contact identified in the table or interactive map, and provide notification prior to entering the airspace. These operators must make every effort to coordinate with the designated facility to deconflict the UAS flight operation with any safety or security concerns stated by the facility and/or sponsoring Federal agency.3). The UAS flight operation is conducted in direct support of a significant and urgent governmental interest and is approved by the FAA’s System Operations Support Center (SOSC) in advance of entering the TFR. Note: UAS operators, that meet the criteria for thisprovision , may also qualify for access under provision 2 outlined above and are encouraged to coordinate directly with the facility’s designated point of contact identified in the table or interactive map, by providing notification prior to entering the airspace and taking into consideration any safety or security concerns stated by the facility and/or sponsoring Federal agency. For urgent and time sensitive requests, contact the FAA’s SOSC at (202) 267-8276 for expedited assistance.  The FAA’s SOSC will coordinate with the facility and/or sponsoring Federal agency as appropriate.ARE THERE OTHER REQUIREMENTS TO OPERATE IN A TFR IN ADDITION TO THE EXCEPTIONS?Separate and distinct from any of the conditions cited above used to gain access to a TFR defined by NOTAM FDC 7/7282 and described in this website, UAS operators must comply with all applicable Federal Aviation Regulations.  For example:For Model Aircraft:·       Comply with 14 CFR Part 101, Subpart E NOTE: These provisions require model aircraft operators to notify any airport operator and air traffic control tower within 5 miles of the intended area of flight.For All Other UAS Operators:·       Comply with a Public Aircraft Certificate of Authorization or Waiver (COA), or·       Comply with 14 CFR Part107, Small Unmanned Aircraft Systems, or·       Comply with Section 333 Exemption and a Certificate of Authorization or Waiver (COA) NOTE: Public and civil UAS operators flying under the provisions of a COA or 14 CFR Part 107 may need to secure further airspace authorizations or waivers in order to conduct the proposed flight operation in controlled airspace, which may overlap with one of the TFRs defined by NOTAM FDC 7/7282 and this website.  In those cases, these operators should follow the pre-existing procedures outlined below. A.     Non-emergency requests for UAS airspace authorizations and waivers must be submitted using the regular process as follows:·       14 CFR Part 107 requests for airspace authorizations and waivers must be submitted to the FAA athttps://www.faa.gov/uas/request_waiver/·        Section 333 Exemption holders may request a site specific COA at https://oeaaa.faa.gov/oeaaa/external/uas/portal.jsp·       Public aircraft operators without an existing authorization to operate must secure a public COA athttps://ioeaaa.faa.gov/oeaaa/Welcome.jsp B.     Emergency requests for UAS authorizations/waivers for missions that directly support significant and urgent governmental interests (e.g., active national defense, homeland security, law enforcement, and emergency operations missions), which cannot be supported by the FAA’s routine authorization/waiver processes should be referred to the SOSC at (202) 267-8276ADDITIONAL QUESTIONS?If you have any general questions regarding UAS operations, please refer to the following FAA webpage: https://www.faa.gov/uas/ , or contact the FAA by email at uashelp@faa.gov or by phone at (844) FLY-MY-UA.If you have any additional questions regarding the TFRs defined by NOTAM FDC 7/7282 and this website, please contact the FAA SOSC at (202) 267-8276.DisclaimersThe restrictions depicted on this site reflect temporary flight restrictions issued for national security reasons at select U.S. Federal facilities. There may be additional temporary flight restrictions that prohibit UAS and manned flight in effect in your area. Seehttp://tfr.faa.gov/tfr2/list.html for additional information on flight restrictions that may be in effect in your area before operating your UAS.</gco:CharacterString>
                    </useLimitation>
                </MD_Constraints>
            </resourceConstraints>
            <language gco:nilReason="missing"/>
            <characterSet>
                <MD_CharacterSetCode codeList="http://www.isotc211.org/2005/resources/Codelist/gmxCodelists.xml#MD_CharacterSetCode" codeListValue="utf8" codeSpace="ISOTC211/19115">utf8</MD_CharacterSetCode>
            </characterSet>
        </MD_DataIdentification>
    </identificationInfo>
</MD_Metadata>
